上溯至宇宙初始 周遭还只是一片漆黑
In the beginning, there was darkness.
不知何时 忽地一声巨响
And then... Bang!
时间空间以及物质皆由此发端
Giving birth to an endless expanding existence
此后不断膨胀 延伸 永无止境
of time, space, and matter.
每一天 新的发现都在不断为我们解开
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking
蕴藏于这里的那些神秘莫测
the mysterious, the mind-blowing,
令人大开眼界 致命的秘密
the deadly secrets of a place we call
我们称这个地方为"宇宙"
the universe.
宇宙的数字让人类智力感到惊恐
The numbers of the universe boggle the human mind.
在可观察到的那部分宇宙里
In the observable part of the universe,
有无数的物体 比如1 000亿个星系
there is something like 100 billion galaxies
而每一个星系有数十亿的恒星
Each with billions of stars.
仙女座星系大约距离我们250万光年
The Andromeda galaxy is about 2.5 million light-years away.
地球围绕太阳运行的速度
The Earth is orbiting the Sun
约为66 000英里/小时
at a speed of about 66,000 miles per hour.
要去理解如此巨大的尺寸 距离和速度
Most of us give up even trying to comprehend such titanic sizes,
我们大多数人会举手投降
distances, and speeds.
有办法能把宇宙的一部分请到地球
But are there ways to bring the sweep of the cosmos down to Earth
帮助我们去了解它
to help us understand
有多大 多远和多快吗？
to help us understand how big, how far, and how fast?
宇宙:多大 多远 多快
行星地球
Planet Earth
把它所有的辽阔土地 深深海洋和崇山峻岭
For all its wide expanses, deep seas,
都加起来
and massive mountains
也不过是一颗小尘埃
Amounts to a speck of dust
如果与广袤的宇宙相比较的话
when stacked up against the immensity of the cosmos.
宇宙可观察得到的部分
The observable universe contains on
包含大约1 000亿个星系
the order of 100 billion galaxies.
而每一个星系 比如银河 包含着大约1 000亿颗恒星
And then each galaxy, like the Milky Way, contains on the order of 100 billion stars.
数字快速攀升到百万级 十亿级
The numbers quickly get up into the millions and then the billions
甚至达到万亿级
and even the trillions.
我们完全丧失了感觉 不知道它的意义
And by then, we've really lost all sense of what that really means.
人类的智力适宜于处理
The human mind is finely tuned
日常生活中遇到的规模
to deal with the scale of day-to-day experience.
大脑能明白一天50英里的旅行
The brain can understand traveling 50 miles in a day.
但500 000英里呢？
But what about 500,000?
有人也许知道
And a person may know what it's
每小时100英里移动是怎样的
And a person may know what it's like to move at 100 miles per hour.
但每小时1亿英里呢？
But what about 100 million?
数字达到百万 十亿和万亿级别时
Numbers like millions and billions, and certainly trillions,
对大多数人来说 很难以想象了
are very hard for most people to imagine,
因为 平心而论 大多数人
because, frankly, most of us
没有十亿或万亿的东西
don't have billions or trillions of anything.
所以 如果大脑不能理解宇宙级的规模
So how can we ever know the universe
我们怎样才能去了解宇宙它呢？
if our brains can't really comprehend its massive scale?
对宇宙物体建立比例模型 能帮上这个忙
Doing scale models of objects in the universe is really helpful,
因为这样能把它们按比例缩小到
because it brings them down to sizes
我们能想像的大小 日常生活里见到的大小
that we can imagine, that we do see in our normal, everyday lives.
我们首先把夜空中的那些大牌主角
We can start by cutting the biggest players of the night sky
行星 恒星和星系
Planets, stars and galaxies
按地球物体的比例缩小
Down to an earthly scale.
有两种方式去形容大小
There are two ways to evaluate size.
我们可以测量其尺寸-- 高度 长度和宽度
We can measure dimensions--Meaning height, length and width
或者计算它的体积 也就是质量
or calculate bulk, also known as mass.
但大体积不总是意味着大质量
Bigger doesn't always mean more massive.
比方说 一个气球与保龄球体积相同
Let's say a balloon has the same volume as a bowling ball.
但保龄球更重 因为它密度大
But the bowling ball has more mass, because it's denser...
它把更多的质量塞进同样的体积里
It's just got more mass crammed into that same volume.
为帮助我们理解宇宙里的一些超级大家伙
To help get a grasp on some of the immense masses floating around our universe,
天文学家劳拉.丹丽参观了一场怪兽车比赛
astronomer Laura Danly visits a monster truck rally...
那里经常有质量非常悬殊的物体相互碰撞
A place where objects of hugely differing masses often collide.
从小玩具车到特大怪兽车 我们无所不有
We' got everything from a small toy truck to the giant monster truck...
一系列的不同质量
And that gives us a range of mass
将帮助我们去了解
that will help us understand
太阳系里的物体互比质量会如何
how massive things are in our Solar System compared to each other,
太阳与其它恒星比较质量又如何
and how massive our own Sun is compared to some other stars.
我们从木星开始比较
We begin the comparison with Jupiter,
它理所当然地被认为是行星之王
known as the king of planets, and for good reason.
因为它的质量超过了4 000亿亿亿磅
Its mass amounts to more than 4 octillion pounds...
也就是说 数字4后面跟着27个零
That's a four followed by 27 zeros.
换而言之 超过300个地球
Put another way, it would take more than 300 Earths
才能相当于木星的质量
to match Jupiter's mass.
但即便如此 它与太阳相比还是微不足道
But even that is measly when compared to the Sun.
太阳是我们太阳系里迄今为止最重的事物
The Sun is by far the most massive thing in our Solar System.
木星是最大的行星 但它比木星重1 000倍
It's about 1,000 times more massive than Jupiter, the biggest planet.
相比之下 在我后面的这辆车大约3 000磅
Well, by comparison, this car behind me is about 3,000 pounds,
而这架小玩具卡车大约3磅
and this little toy truck is about 3 pounds.
所以 它们的差异与太阳和木星的差异相当
So that's about the same difference between the Sun and Jupiter.
这是一边倒的差异 3 000磅很好地说明了问题
It's a crushing difference, as 3,000 pounds make perfectly clear.
但要记住 这是怪兽车比赛
But remember, this is a monster truck rally,
代表我们太阳的这辆烂车
and the junk car representing our Sun
也许会后悔招惹了"小木星"
may regret picking on little Jupiter.
太阳是我们太阳系质量最大的物体
The Sun is the most massive object in our Solar System,
不过它不是银河系质量最大的恒星
but it's not the most massive star in the galaxy.
有许多恒星的质量比太阳大
There are a lot of stars more massive than the Sun.
为了表现太阳和更大质量的恒星之间的悬殊
To envision the disparity between the Sun and a more massive star
我们假设这辆3 000磅的烂车就是太阳
Let's keep the 3,000-pound junk car as the Sun
让它去对抗一辆10 000磅的怪兽车
and put it up against a 10,000-pound monster truck
这辆怪兽车代表在75光年之外的一颗恒星
representing a star some 75 light-years away.
这辆车和怪兽车的差异
The difference between the monster truck and the car
接近于天狮星这颗恒星和我们太阳的差异
is about the same difference as a star called Regulus...
明亮的天狮星
The bright star right in the middle of Leo,
位于天狮座正中间 质量是太阳的3.5倍
about 3 1/2 times as massive as our Sun.
多三倍的质量看起来不多
Three times more massive may not seem like much,
但别忘了
but don't forget
我们现在是用银河巨兽在相互对抗
we're now pitting galactic giants against each other.
嗯 真让人震惊
Well, that was quite a shock.
正如所见
But as you can see,
质量差异三倍 下场迥然不同
three times the mass difference makes a difference.
如果我们让天狮星骑在太阳顶上
If we could somehow bring Regulus here and have it sit on top of this Sun,
结果几乎一样
that's about the same comparison.
但即使是健壮如怪兽车的天狮星
But even monster truck-sized Regulus
也不能与宇宙里质量巨大的
can't stack up to the immense mass
真正巨人相比较
mass of the true titans of the universe.
绕银河系旋转的已知最重恒星
The most massive star we know orbits around the Milky Way...
位于银河的伴星系"大麦哲伦云"里面
A little companion galaxy called the Large Magellanic Cloud...
处在"蜘蛛星云"的中部
In the middle of a nebula called the Tarantula Nebula.
这颗恒星有一个比较无聊的名字--R136A
That star has a kind of boring name...R136A
但它却是一颗非常重的恒星
but it's still a very massive star.
R136A是一颗年青的恒星
R136A is a young star
大约一百万岁
about a million years old.
它的表面温度是70 000度
Its surface temperature is 70,000 degrees
比我们太阳的温度高大约7倍
about 7 times hotter than our Sun.
在2010年之前
Before 2010, stars were thought
恒星被认为不可能形成超过太阳150倍的质量
stars were thought to form no bigger than 150 times the mass of the Sun.
但新近的发现达到这个极限的2倍
But new discoveries have doubled that limit.
我们认为R136A的质量可能是太阳的250倍
We think R136A is probably about 250,
也许会是300倍
maybe as much as 300 times the mass of our Sun.
为了代表这个大质量的恒星
To represent this massive star,
你需要找到一辆真正巨大的卡车
you need a truly monstrous truck.
这个怪兽要比这辆车重100倍
This monster is 100 times heavier.
明明是极端质量 却用小包装
But extreme mass also comes in small packages,
密度就会让重力变得激进起来
where density takes the force of gravity into radical territory.
对问题采取剧烈大爆炸的方式解决
The greatest massive bang for the buck we can see in the universe
我们在宇宙中能见到的例子是中子星
comes from a stellar object known as a neutron star.
中子星是超新星爆炸遗留下来的核心
A neutron star is the leftover core of a supernova explosion,
它拥有惊人的致密质量
with its mass packed astoundingly tight.
它相当于把太阳全部质量的1.5倍
It's got 1 1/2 times all of the mass of our Sun
强行塞入到约10英里直径的体积内
crammed into a volume of about 10 miles across.
如果把一辆怪兽车塞入到方糖大小的空间
If you crammed one monster truck down into the size of a sugar cube,
那样也比不上中子星那么致密
that would not be anywhere close to as dense as a neutron star.
得把一千万辆怪兽车塞入到方糖大小的空间
I'd need 10 million monster trucks crashed down
那才可以
into the size of a sugar cube.
把许多一千万辆怪兽车做成的方糖码起来
Stack these 10 million monster truck sugar
高和宽都是10英里
cubes ten miles high and wide,
你就获得一个属于自己的中子星了
and you've got yourself a neutron star.
中子星是离奇的极端物体
Neutron stars are just bizarrely extreme objects.
如果你企图登上中子星 那绝对不可能
If you were to try to land on a neutron star,
因为你会发现
it would be absolutely impossible,
在中子星上
because you would find that on the neutron star
你的重量大约是地球上的50亿倍
you weigh about 5 billion times more than you do here on Earth.
但是 要去寻找恒星最大能有多大
But mass isn't everything when it comes to finding out just
不能光看质量
how big the biggest stars can be.
在宇宙里 还有许多巨人
The universe is also filled with the titans
其数量多到难以想象
that take up unimaginable amounts of space.
在地球上 我们见到的一些小如针尖的光线
Some of the tiny pinpricks of light we see from Earth
事实上是大到足以吞下整个太阳系的恒星
are actually stars big enough to swallow our entire Solar System.
哪怕只是银河里的最大恒星
Can the human mind even comprehend
人类的智力能理解吗？
the largest star in the galaxy?
我们让广袤宇宙的尺寸 速度和距离
We're bringing the sizes, speeds, and distances
按比例缩小到
of our vast universe
人类智力可以理解的程度
down to a scale the human mind can comprehend.
在我们太阳系里 目前最大的东西是太阳
The biggest thing in our Solar System by far is the Sun.
就质量而言
In terms of sheer mass,
它比地球重300 000倍
it weighs over 300,000 times more than the Earth.
而在体积上
But in terms of volume, it's also the Solar System's
它也是太阳系里物理上最大的物体
it's also the Solar System's physically largest object,
直径达到870 000英里
at 870,000 miles across.
所以太阳比地球大
So the Sun is really big compared to the Earth.
它比地球大109倍
It's 109 times as wide as the Earth.
这意味着 超过一百万个地球
That actually means that over a million Earths
才能填满太阳的体积
could fit inside the volume of the Sun.
真的很大
It's really big.
但是 虽然太阳在世人眼中巨大无比
But as enormous as the Sun is in earthly terms,
当它与银河里的庞然大物相比较时
our home star seems puny when stacked against
看起来却是那么的微小
our galaxy's lineup of stellar mammoths.
取自历史和科学范畴的奇怪名字
With strange names taken from history and science,
赋予了恒星别样的意义
they push the envelope of what it means to be a star.
让我们逐个数一数
Consider them in turn...
织女星
Vega...
参宿五
Bellatrix...
弧矢七
Epsilon Canis Majoris...
天枢星
Dubhe...
毕宿五
Aldebaran...
最后是…
And finally,
超级巨大的参宿四
the super-enormous Betelgeuse...
和大犬座VY
And VY Canis Majoris.
哗
Oh, wow.
天文学家阿历斯.菲利朋欧
Astronomer Alex Filippenko attempts
试图将它们带到地球上的一个飞机库内
to bring them down to Earth in an airplane hangar.
我们今天会在飞机库里
We're here in this airport hangar today
尝试说明恒星 尤其是大恒星的相对大小
in order to try and illustrate the relative sizes of stars, in particular big stars.
我们将对一些气球充气
We're going to inflate some balloons, and even some really
包括某些用于气象的大气球
big weather balloons, and show them in comparison with the Sun,
用它们与代表太阳的保龄球作比较
which we've scaled down to the size of a bowling ball.
代表太阳的保龄球直径8.5英寸
The bowling-ball sun is 8 1/2 inches across,
相比之下 地球不会比一颗小珠子大
which would make the Earth no bigger than a tiny bead.
我的两个助理是气球专家
My two assistants are balloon experts...
不但知道如何用氦来充气并扎好
they know how to inflate balloons with helium and tie them off,
也知道需要充多少的气
and they know how much to inflate them.
他们将通过充气 让不同气球的大小不同
So they're going to inflate these different balloons to different sizes.
对气球充气 将让我们见识到按比例缩小的
Inflating the balloons will take us on a scaled-down tour of
太阳的大兄弟 大大兄弟和最大的兄弟
the Sun's big, bigger, and biggest brothers.
第一站 织女星
First stop... The star Vega.
位于天琴座内的织女星
Located in the constellation Lyra,
是夜空中最亮的五颗恒星之一
Vega is one of the five brightest stars in the night sky.
它发出蓝白色的光 因为它比太阳更高温
It glows blue-white, because it burns hotter than our Sun.
好了 我把"保龄球太阳"拿到这里了
Okay, so I've got my bowling-ball Sun here.
伙计 这气球多大？
Guys, how big is this balloon?
我们测量一下
Let's check it out.
约2英尺
Right about 2 feet.
2英尺 所以这是保龄球尺寸的
2 feet. So that's... that's about 2 1/2 times the
2.5倍
size of the bowling ball.
说明它象织女星
So that's like the star Vega.
织女星是一颗25光年远的青白色恒星
It's a bluish white star, 25 light-years away...
在天空里非常明亮
Very bright star in the sky.
接下来是参宿五
Next up is Bellatrix,
位于最亮的星座--猎户座里
a star in Orion The Hunter...
是一颗恒星
the brightest constellation in the sky.
鼎鼎大名的猎户座有明显的躯干和腰带
Well-known stars pinpoint its torso and belt.
另一颗蓝巨星 即参宿五 是它的右肩（注:应为左肩）
Another blue giant, Bellatrix is at Orion's right shoulder
其光亮可照射到240光年远
and shines 240 light-years away.
这气球更大一点
So here's a bigger balloon.
尺寸多少？
What's its size?
4英尺
This is 4 feet.
4英尺 这就是说 它的大小是"保龄球太阳"的5.5倍
4 feet... So that's about 5 1/2 times the size of my bowling ball... my Sun.
所以这是更大一点的恒星 比较象参宿五
So this is a bigger star, it's kind of like Bellatrix.
比参宿五还大的
Bigger than Bellatrix
是炽热的蓝色恒星"阿哈拉"
is the hot blue star Adhara
也被称为"大犬座弧矢七"
also known as Epsilon Canis Majoris.
"大犬座"这个星座名字 翻译过来就是"大狗"的意思
Canis Majoris is a constellation whose name translates as "The Great Dog."
哗 眼前一个大恒星 不是吗？
Wow, now here's a big star, huh?
这一个12英尺
This one is 12 feet.
这个东西比太阳大17倍
This thing is 17 times wider than the Sun.
象弧矢七位于大犬座一样
That's kind of like the star Epsilon Canis Majoris in the constellation Canis Major.
天狼星也位于这个星座里
That's the same constellation that Sirius is in.
天狼星是天空里最明亮的恒星
Sirius is the brightest star in the sky,
但这是因为弧矢七远在430光年之外
but Epsilon Canis Majoris is 430 light-years away.
如果和天狼星处在同样的距离 弧矢七会亮15倍
If it were at the same distance as Sirius, it would appear 15 times brighter.
比弧矢七差不多大两倍的
Almost twice as big as Epsilon Canis Majoris
是天枢星
is Dubhe,
它是一颗位于北斗七星边缘的巨大恒星
a giant star on the lip of the Big Dipper,
距离我们120光年
120 light-years away.
哗 酷
Wow, cool.
我看到了一个更大的气球
Well, here I see an even bigger balloon.
直径是多少？
What's its diameter?
看一看
Let's see.
21英尺
21 feet.
差不多是我的"保龄球太阳"的30倍
So that's about 30 of my bowling-ball Suns.
事实上 它接近天枢星的大小
In fact, that's about the size of the star Dubhe.
天枢星不同于我们见到的其它恒星
That star Dubhe is different from the others that we've seen...
它是所谓的红巨星
it's what's called a red giant.
颜色近似橙色
It's got kind of an orange color.
比起之前见到的蓝白色恒星 它要冷一些
It's cooler than the blue-white ones that we've seen previously.
令人惊奇的是 还有一些恒星更大
Amazingly, stars come in larger sizes still.
即使是飞机库也容纳不下它们
And even an airplane hangar isn't big enough to contain them.
我们在这里放置毕宿五
Here's where we have to place Aldebaran...
这颗巨大的恒星从古代开始就很出名
a monster star known since ancient times,
一度被认为是财富和荣誉的象征
and once thought to be a sign of riches and honor.
这个气球直径大约32英尺
This balloon is about 32 feet across.
比代表我们太阳的保龄球
Now, that's roughly 45 times bigger than this bowling ball
它差不多大45倍
which represents our Sun.
这就是位于金牛座里的恒星毕宿五
Now, this balloon then is about the size of the star Aldebaran,
这颗红巨星的大小
a red giant in Taurus the bull.
它距离地球68光年
It's about 65 light-years away,
其真正颜色接近橙色
and its true color is roughly orange.
然则 气球再大 也不足以去代表
Now even the biggest balloons fall short in
银河里最大的那些恒星的大小
representing the size of the galaxy's biggest stars.
比如参宿四 就是另一颗在猎户座里的恒星
Betelgeuse, for instance, is another star in orion.
距离我们650光年的它
650 light-years away,
比太阳大一千倍
it is a thousand times the size of the Sun.
参宿四是如此的大
Betelgeuse is so large
如果它在太阳系中心 其半径几乎会伸展到木星的轨道
that its radius would extend roughly to the orbit of Jupiter.
所以 参宿四如果真在太阳系里面
So if Betelgeuse was actually in the Solar System,
那么八大行星要么都毁灭
then all of the eight planets would be completely
要么都太热 不适宜居住
either destroyed or totally too hot to be habitable.
但最大的已知恒星另有他人
- But the largest known star is a beast
一个叫大犬座VY的讨厌鬼
by the name of VY Canis Majoris.
根据一些人的预测 它的直径比太阳大2 000倍
By some estimates, it extends to 2,000 times the diameter of our Sun.
这是一颗不折不扣的巨大恒星
That is a truly gargantuan star.
如果有一架民用飞机就在大犬座VY的外侧
If there were a commercial airplane flying just outside VY Canis Majoris,
那么飞机要花1 200年才能绕行一周
it would take about 1,200 years to fully circle it.
这样大级别的任何物体
Any object on this enormous scale
作为宇宙有多大这个问题的恐怖答案
seems truly alien to the human mind...
对人类智力来说 看起来真是不可思议
An intimidating answer to the "how big" question about the universe.
"多远？"同样令人烦恼
No less discomforting is "how far?"
因为行星 恒星和星系之间的距离
Because distances between planets, stars, and galaxies
伸展到了人类的全部经验之外
stretch beyond all human experience.
所以有效的好方法是
So a really great way of bringing it home
将一切按比例缩小到接近于人类的尺度
is to scale everything down to a more human scale.
比起抽象的绝对数值 事物的相对大小
We are better at understanding the relative sizes of things
让我们更容易明白
than abstract absolute numbers.
比如月亮
Take the Moon.
它与地球的距离比250 000英里少一点
It lies a little less than 250,000 miles from Earth.
你可能认为这不是太远
You might think this isn't all that far.
嗯 再想想吧
Well, think again.
想象一下地球缩小到篮球那么大的情景
Imagine if I shrank the Earth down to about the size of a basketball.
所以 如果地球象这个物体这么大
So if the Earth was about the size of this object here,
我敢说 月亮就只有这个网球那么大
I would actually have the Moon be about the size of this tennis ball.
可能你接下来会问
So the next question you might ask is,
"物体的相对大小确定了"
"given the relative sizes of these things,
"它们之间的距离有多远呢？"
how far apart are they going to be from each other?"
为了向你说明 我需要一些帮助
To show you, I'm actually going to need some help.
于是约翰尼将帮我拿着地球
So Johnny is actually going to hold the Earth for me
而我则带着月亮和尺子走到相应远的地方
while I actually take the Moon and measure out how far away it needs to be.
开始
So here it goes.
1英尺 2英尺…
1 foot, 2 feet...
一路算来 我们已到了10英尺
All the way back, we're already at 10 feet.
或许要走远一些…
Probably go even more...
超过15英尺了 但还得走
Already past 15. We've got to go much further.
这里… 21英尺
And here we are... at 21 feet.
这就是用比例法得到的月亮离地球有多远
That's actually how far away the Moon is from the Earth in our scale model.
239 000英里 这个地月距离
At 239,000 miles,
因为阿波罗登月任务的缘故
the Earth-Moon distance has now become familiar to us,
被我们大家所熟悉
because of Apollo missions to the Moon.
这是少数我们能真正明白的天文跨度之一
This is one of the few astronomical spans we can readily understand.
通过6次载人登月活动
In six manned Moon landings,
我们知道了地月之间的旅行时间是三天多一点点
we learned that the travel time was a little more than three days.
而与月球的来往成为了我们集体知识的一部分
And the lunar commute has become a part of our collective knowledge.
发动机停止
Engine stop.
好的 休斯顿 挑战者号着陆了
Okay, Houston, the Challenger has landed.
但在月亮之外 太阳系把距离这一概念
But beyond the Moon, the Solar System extends
延伸到非常遥远的地方
to distances so vast,
我们有限的智力再次应付不了这件苦差事
again, our limited minds aren't really up to the task.
不过 如果我们
But what would happen
能把所有行星带到地球 会是怎样的情景呢？
if we literally brought all the planets down to Earth?
这样就能够明白无误地说明
It can be overwhelming to consider how big,
我们宇宙里的一切是多大 多远和多快
how far, and how fast everything is in our universe.
即使只是在我们太阳系里
Even in our Solar System,
距离已经大到几乎难以想像的程度
the distances are almost unimaginably vast.
所以我们要缩小太阳系 才能把它带到地球上
That's why we're shrinking our Solar System and bringing it down to Earth.
想象一下 如果我们把
Imagine if we took the 870,000 miles
直径870 000英里的太阳
of diameter of the Sun and shrank it down
缩小到保龄球这样大小
to the size of a bowling ball.
行星会怎么样？
What would that do to the planets?
嗯 我们已经把它们缩小在这里了
Well, we'd have to shrink them down to sizes that we have here.
于是 从水星一直到海王星
So we have the eight planets of the Solar System lined out,
我们得到了排成一行的太阳系八大行星
starting with Mercury all the way out to Neptune.
在这个比例模型里 我们的地球家园
So in this scale model, our Earth, our home,
在太阳是这个保龄球时 它是一个小珠子
is this tiny little bead, while the Sun is this bowling ball.
这些"小珠子和弹珠行星"与"保龄球太阳"的大小是成比例的
These bead and marble planets may be to scale with the bowling ball Sun,
但它们的间距并非眼前的样子
but the distances between them aren't.
为了说明这一切 物理学家克里福特.约翰逊
To demonstrate that, physicist Clifford Johnson
将在一条跑道上展示这个微型太阳系
is going to walk the length of this miniature Solar System laid out along a runway.
这是约翰逊
I have Johnny here, who's going to help me
他将帮我用计距器来测量距离
measure the distances with this surveyor's wheel.
好了 我们去探测太阳系吧
Okay, so let's go and explore the Solar System.
开始
Let's do it.
在这个按比例缩小的太阳系里
Each foot in this scaled-down Solar System
每英尺代表着行星之间100万英里的距离
represents 1 million miles in the distances between the planets.
我们到了水星
And here we are at Mercury.
36英尺
And that's 36 feet.
在实际当中 它距离太阳是360万英里
In reality, it's actually about 36 million miles away from the Sun.
在太阳系里 第一个行星与太阳距离有多远
It's amazing just how far the very first planet
让人惊异
of the Solar System is from the Sun.
现在 我们向第二个行星进发
So now let's go on to the second planet.
好
Yeah.
我们到金星了
So here we are at Venus.
距离是67英尺
And that's 67 feet.
因此 这个小不点代表着金星到太阳的距离
So this bead representing Venus is about twice as far
是水星的两倍
from the Sun as Mercury is.
事实上的距离 则是670万英里
It's actually, in reality, about 67 million miles away.
我们到地球了
And here we are at the Earth.
93英尺
And that's 93 feet.
这个弹珠在这里代表着地球
We have the Earth here represented by this marble.
它实际上距离太阳930万英里
And, in fact, it's in reality 93 million miles away from the Sun.
从这里见到的保龄球
The way the bowling ball looks, in terms of the size,
与我们天空里的太阳
from here, is about the size
大小很接近
the sun appears in our sky.
蓝色珠子代表地球
We have this blue bead representing the Earth.
而在大约2.5英寸之外 有一颗小得多的珠子
And about 2 1/2 inches away, we have a much smaller bead
它代表着月亮
representing the Moon.
还记得比例不一样时的情形吧
Remember that on a different scale,
当地球如同篮球大小时
with Earth the size of a basketball,
月亮是在21英尺之外
the Moon was 21 feet away.
为了让整个太阳系都出现在画面里
To bring the whole Solar System into the picture,
我们只能把地月距离按比例缩小到几英寸
we've had to scale down the Earth-Moon distance to mere inches.
眼前这微小的地月距离
This tiny distance between the Earth and Moon
是迄今为止载人太空探险的极限
is the limit so far of manned exploration of space.
希望我们在未来日子里做得更多和更好
Hopefully, we'll do a lot better in the years to come.
在我们跑道上 火星运行在地球之外49英尺的地方
On our runway, Mars orbits another 49 feet away,
即距离太阳大约1 420万英里
or almost 142 million miles from the Sun.
在火星之外 这次的距离就非常非常远了
The distances beyond Mars are about to get much, much larger.
我们到了木星
Here we are... Jupiter.
现在离太阳是484英尺
We're at 484 feet from the Sun.
是火星到太阳距离的三倍
That's actually three times as far from the Sun as Mars is.
神奇的是 这个距离里的所有小不点
With all this space between these tiny marbles,
就是我们从地球用肉眼能看到的行星
it's a wonder we can see the planets from Earth at all.
它说明了太阳极为明亮
It tells us that the Sun is incredibly bright...
所以阳光能照射到这些天体 并被它们反射回地球
So that the light from the Sun can go out to these bodies, reflect off them,
因此我们能用肉眼看到它们
and then come back to here on Earth for us to see them.
好了 向外面的土星前进
Okay, onwards and outwards to Saturn.
好 出发
All right, here we go.
我们这两位太空探险者发现 土星距离太阳886英尺
Our two space explorers find Saturn 886 feet from the Sun.
在现实当中 土星距离太阳8 860英里
In fact, Saturn, at 886 million miles away from the Sun,
差不多是木星到太阳距离的两倍
is almost twice the distance from the Sun that Jupiter is from the Sun.
所以说 我们走得相当远了
So we've come a huge extra distance
不过 还没有走完整个太阳系
and we're not even done with the Solar System yet.
在1 800英尺的地方
At 1,800 feet, the scaled orbit of Uranus stands
矗立着按比例缩小的天王星 它比土星远两倍
the scaled orbit of Uranus stands twice as far as Saturn...
即距离太阳18亿英里
1.8 billion miles from the Sun.
我难以看清后面的太阳
I can hardly see the Sun back there.
同时几乎看不到我们的下一站
And I can actually hardly see Neptune in the distance,
位于远处的海王星
which is our next stop on our journey.
走吧？
Shall we go?
走
Let's go.
天哪 好远
Jeez, that's far.
是啊
Yep.
我们到了最后一个行星--海王星
And here we are... Neptune... the last of the planets.
距离太阳是2 798英尺
2,798 feet from our Sun.
这个结果换算为现实世界里的距离时
That from our model translates into the real-world distance
从海王星到太阳 距离大约是30亿英里
of almost 3 billion miles that Neptune is away from the Sun.
距离越远 恒星要花越长的时间去环绕太阳一周
This far out, a planet takes a long time to do an orbit around the Sun.
海王星上的一年 大约是165个地球年
The neptunian year is about 165 of our Earth years.
说起来 我们是在一个海王星年之前
In fact, only one of those neptunian years has passed since
才发现了海王星
Neptune was actually discovered.
通过这次测量
Viewed on this scale,
让人惊奇的是太阳万有引力的影响无处不在
it's a wonder the Sun's gravity has any effect at all.
甚至还影响到太阳系里在海王星之外的天体
And there's still more to the Solar System beyond Neptune...
包括较小的天体 比如冥王星
Including smaller bodies, like Pluto...
以及差不多距离1光年远的黑暗寒冷的彗星群
And then, nearly a light-year away, clouds of dark icy comets.
如果说我们太阳系里行星的间距
If the space between the planets in our Solar System
让人类的理解感到吃力
strains human comprehension,
那么恒星之间和星系之间的巨大间距
then the vast distances between stars and galaxies
就会把它压垮
totally overwhelms it.
天文学家怎么知道恒星有多远
That astronomers even know how far away stars are
纽约布鲁克林的诺拉对此觉得迷惑不解
is a mystery to Nora from Brooklyn, New York,
她想…
who wants to...
咨询《宇宙》团队
"我们怎样测量恒星间和星系间的距离？"
How do we measure the distance to stars and galaxies?
诺拉 这问题非常复杂
Nora, that's actually a pretty complex question.
对大多数附近的恒星 由于地球围绕太阳运行
For the most nearby stars, we look at how their positions
我们观察它们在天上随时间变化而变化的位置
in the sky change with time as Earth orbits the Sun.
对更遥远的恒星 或其它星系的恒星
For more distant stars, or stars in other galaxies,
我们测量它们有多亮 与它们已知的功率相比较
we measure how bright they appear to be, compare that with their known power,
这样来确定它们的距离
and thus determine their distance.
它们的距离是如此遥远
They are distances so immense
以至于"多大"和"多远"
that "how big" and "how far"
成为挑战每一个人理解力的问题
are questions to challenge anyone's power of comprehension.
不仅如此 宇宙的大量级也扩展到了速度范畴
But the magnitudes of the universe also extend to speed.
科学家发现宇宙是一个超高速的赛车场
What scientists have discovered is that the universe is super-velocity racetrack
即使是巨大的行星
where even giant planets
也比飞行的子弹快
move faster than speeding bullets.
我们已经见识了太空里的事物有多大和多远
We've seen how big and how far things are in space.
现在我们要去看看有多快
Now we're going to see how fast.
为了这个目标 我们首先要明白
To do that, first we have to understand
被称为光年的天文量尺
the celestial measuring stick known as the light-year.
正如它的称呼 一光年是指
Just like it sounds, one light-year is the distance
光线在一年里走过的距离
light travels in one year.
大约是6万亿英里
That amounts to about 6 trillion miles.
但这并不能帮助我们去理解光本身有多快
But that doesn't help us understand how fast light speed itself is.
光的速度很快 大约186 000英里/秒
The speed of light is really fast... about 186,000 miles per second.
没有实例是难以理解的
Now that's hard to conceive without an example,
想象一下光在洛杉矶和纽约之间来回折返吧
imagine light were bouncing back and forth between Los Angeles and New York.
在一秒内 它能来回38次
It could do 38 back-and-forth bounces in one second.
为了让光速这一概念更具体
In an effort to chase down the concept of the speed of light,
天文学家格雷格.劳克林与兵器专家迈克尔.沃伊特
astronomer Greg Laughlin teams with firearms expert Michael Voight
一起展示一些在地球上移动速度最快的物体
to demonstrate some of the fastest moving objects on Earth.
我们将把光的速度
The way we're going to do that is to compare the speed of light
与地球上速度快的东西作比较
to the speed of something that's really fast here on Earth,
它就是子弹
which are bullets.
前方有一个靶子 当子弹打中它时
We've got a target downrange so when it hits it,
你会听到响声
you'll hear that ding on the end of it.
你就能大致明白花了多少时间
And you can kind of see how long that actually takes.
这是.204鲁格步枪子弹
This is a .204 Ruger.
它是地球上目前飞得最快的民用枪支子弹
This is the fastest commercial cartridge on the planet right now.
距离是300码
We've got a 300-yard travel,
所以我要努力去感觉
so I'm really going to try to get a sense of the time that it takes
子弹飞至靶子所花的时间
for that bullet to travel downrange.
拭目以待吧
So let's see how that works.
好枪法
Nice shot.
伙计 我感觉不出来
Boy, I couldn't get any sense.
我一扣动扳机… 呯… 它就打中靶子了
As soon as I pulled the trigger... boom... it hit the target.
根本来不及感觉子弹的飞行时间
No sense at all of the travel time.
由于人类感官分辨不出这些子弹的速度
Because it's so difficult for the human senses o perceive the speed of these bullets,
迈克尔安排了一个被称为精密计时器的
Mike sets up a highly accurate timing device
精确计时的装置
known as a chronograph.
这套装置里有一个计时器
So this is the unit that the timer's actually in.
里面有一个时钟
Inside, it's got a clock.
- 好的 看来计时器准备好了 - 好
- Okay, it looks like the chronograph's ready here.- All right.
我们打几发子弹后 就知道子弹有多快了
Let's put a couple rounds through here and we'll see how fast this ammo goes.
怎么样？
And what do we have?
哗 结果是4 297英尺/秒
Wow, so that was 4,297 feet per second.
也就是约3 000英里/小时
So that's about 3,000 miles per hour.
- 相当快 - 相当快
- Pretty quick. - Pretty quick.
比1英里/秒稍慢一点
It's a little less than a mile per second.
大致是音速的四倍
That roughly four times the speed of sound.
我深感震憾
So, I mean, I'm impressed.
但与光速相比 它就相形失色了
But that pales in comparison to the speed of light.
在子弹从枪口沿着靶场一路飞驰
In the time that it took for those bullets to go from the muzzle of the gun
到中靶的这段时间里
all the way downrange to hit the target...
光线能不慌不忙地沿着地球表面
During that time, light has enough time to go all the way
从洛杉矶去到巴黎
around the surface of the Earth, from Los Angeles to Paris, and
再用同等时间折返回来
then back in that same amount of time.
光的速度为6亿7千万英里/小时
Moving at 670 million miles per hour,
它完全推翻了地球上的速度体验
light completely demolishes any Earthly experience of speed.
对我来说 感觉不到它多么厉害
That really doesn't mean very much to me,
因为6亿7千万英里 对我们在地球上
because the whole distance of 670 million miles
日常接触到的任何距离来说 太大了
is much larger than any kind of distances that we normally deal here with on Earth.
光的速度与我们世界的速度相差十分悬殊
The speed of light and the speed of our world are so vastly far apart,
为了真正理解其中的差异
we have to take light and slow it down
我们不得不让光慢下来
to really understand the difference.
因此 让我们回到急速飞驰的子弹
For that, we go back to the speeding bullet.
3 000英里/小时的子弹 我们勉强能理解它的快速
At 3,000 miles per hour, we can barely perceive its speed.
如果光的移动不比飞行的子弹快
If light moved no faster than a speeding bullet,
我们周围的世界也同等慢下来
what would happen to the world around us if we slowed it down
那会发生什么事情呢？
by the same amount?
例如民用喷气式飞机
For example, a commercial jet
其飞行速度大约是600英里/小时
travels roughly 600 miles an hour.
所以 假定子弹速度就是光的速度
So assuming the bullet represents the speed of light,
喷气式飞机有多慢呢？
how slow would the jet look?
在光速为3 000英里/小时这个比例下
At the scale where the speed of light is 3,000 miles per hour,
民用喷气式飞机只能用爬行来形容
then that commercial jet is crawling along so that it
它每分钟只能前进3英寸
would take entire minute to travel three inches.
F-15能达到2.5马赫
An F-15 can reach Mach 2.5...
速度超过了1 500英里/小时
that's over 1,500 miles per hour.
但在这个光速慢下来的世界里
But on this slow-light scale, an F-15
F-15需要整整1分钟才能移动7英寸
needs a full minute to move seven inches.
原本急速飞驰的子弹它们呢？
And what about speeding bullets themselves?
它们在这个光速变慢的世界里 看起来有多慢？
How slow do they look on this slow-light scale?
这些高速来福步枪子弹
If we go up to those high-speed rifle bullets,
1分钟只能前进1英尺多一点 大约是13英寸
then they're making it just a little bit more than foot...
如果光的实际速度
over the course of one minute at the scale
是3 000英里/小时的话
where 3,000 miles per hour is the actual speed of light.
现实世界中的蜗牛 速度比它还快两倍
In the real world, a snail moves more than twice as fast.
这说明了许多宇宙物体的速度
As it turns out, much of the cosmos is zipping around at
我们无法真正理解
speeds we can't really comprehend.
运动是宇宙里的正常状态
Motion is actually the normal state of affairs in the universe.
我们可能认为相对地面而言 我们是站立不动的
We may think we're standing still... and we are, relative to the ground...
但地球在围绕着太阳运行
but Earth is orbiting the Sun,
而太阳在围绕着银河中心运行
the Sun is orbiting around the center of our galaxy,
银河则是在围绕着我们本星系群运行
our galaxy is orbiting around in our local group of galaxies.
所有的这些物体都在以非常高的速度移动着
And all of these objects are moving at very high speeds.
地球围绕太阳运行的速度是66 000英里/小时
The Earth is orbiting the Sun at a speed of about 66,000 miles per hour.
这个速度足以让你在一个小时内环绕地球两圈
That's enough to take you around the Earth more than twice in a single hour.
我们太阳绕着银河中心急行军
Our Sun is rushing around the Milky Way center at
速度是483 000英里/小时
483,000 miles per hour.
而银河本身在太空里穿梭的速度
And the Milky Way itself is flying through space at
是130万英里/小时
1.3 million miles per hour.
但光速比它还快600倍
But the speed of light is still over 600 times faster.
这个简单事实说明了
The simple fact remains,
相对宇宙的本质来说 我们生活在一个慢动作的世界里
we live in slow motion compared to the nature of the cosmos.
现代技术无法让我们的移动速度达到接近光速
Modern technology doesn't travel anywhere near the speed of light.
如果我们去旅行 比如说乘坐民用喷气式飞机
If we travel, say, at commercial-jet speed,
它的速度比光速慢100万倍 那么我们要花400万年
which is a million times slower than the speed of light, then it's going
才能跨越遥远距离
to take us on the order of 4 million years to traverse that
去到最近的恒星--太阳
distance to the closest stars to the Sun.
如果要花的时间比整个人类存在的时间还长
If it takes more years to reach the nearest star than the human race has existed,
试问谁能真正明白
how can any person ever really understand
我们银河的大小？
the size of our own galaxy?
通过缩小最大的行星和恒星
By downsizing the biggest planets and stars
以及把光变慢 让它们处于人类体验得到的级别
and the velocity of light speed to the level of human experience,
我们终于能开始明白太空规模的某一些了
we can finally begin to understand some of the scales of outer space.
但是 恒星的间距让人类想象力相形见绌
But is there a way to do the same for the distances between the stars
有办法同样能让我们理解好距离它吗？
distances that utterly dwarf the human imagination?
虽然科学家用光年来计量恒星之间的遥远距离
Although scientists measure the enormous distance between stars in light-years,
但这些数字在帮助我们理解银河的辽阔时 显得很勉强
those numbers barely help us grasp the expansive nature of the galactic landscape.
因此 让我们把一切都缩小到1光年等于1英里的比例
So let's shrink everything down to a scale where one light-year equals one mile.
按这个比例 我们太阳被缩小到一颗砂粒大小
On that scale, our Sun shrinks down to the size of a sand grain.
我们已经计算出有多少的砂粒
We've calculated just how many sand grains,
也就是有多少的恒星在我们银河系里
or how many stars, would fill our own Milky Way galaxy.
其数量
And the number of stars in the Milky Way
与这箱子里的砂粒数量差不多吧
is about the same as the number of sand grains in this chest.
如果你去数 恒星会超过1 000亿颗
If you're counting, that's more than 100 billion stars.
如果1年光等于1英里 最近的恒星会位于哪里呢？
If one light-year equals one mile, where is the nearest star?
洛杉矶的格里菲斯天文台
From the vantage point of the Griffith observatory in Los Angeles,
是天文学家劳拉.丹丽工作的地方
where astronomer Laura Danly works,
从它的最高点算起 最近的砂粒将会位于
the nearest sand grain would end up in Hollywood,
4英里外的好莱坞
four miles away.
为了在拥挤的城市里 能精确定位相隔4英里的砂粒
To help pinpoint sand grains positioned four miles apart in a dense city,
我们将在两地之间使用镜子去来回反射阳光
we'll use mirrors to flash sunlight back and forth between them.
于是亚伦和约翰尼拿上镜子
So Aaron and Johnny have mirrors,
他们将反射阳光
and they're going to reflect sunlight
以帮助我们明白离最近的恒星有多远
to help us see just how far away it is to the nearest star.
所以 我需要取一些恒星带去好莱坞
So I need to get a few stars to take off to Hollywood with me.
行了
That should do.
斯坦 亚伦 好了吗？
So Stan, Aaron, are you ready?
你要扮演太阳 站在格里菲斯天文台这里
You're going to be the Sun staying here at Griffith observatory.
约翰尼和我去外面的好莱坞
Johnny and I are headed out to Hollywood.
好了吗？
You all set?
- 开始吧 - 好的 走
- Let's do it.- All right, let's go.
离我们太阳最近的天上邻居
The nearest celestial neighbor to our Sun
不是单一的恒星
isn't a single star,
相反 它是三颗一起的
but rather a grouping of three.
其中的两颗 半人马座阿尔法星A和B
Two of them... Alpha Centauri "A"and "B"
它们相互围绕运行 都和太阳差不多大小
orbit each other, and are about the same size as our Sun.
第三颗 半人马座比邻星 是一颗红矮星
The third, Proxima Centauri, is a red-dwarf star...
颜色暗淡 而且质量只有兄弟们的10%
dim and only about 10% as massive as its siblings.
我是在好莱坞的一个屋顶上
I'm here on a rooftop in Hollywood,
大约距离远处的格里菲斯天文台4英里
about four miles away from Griffith observatory there in the background.
我手里拿着一个装满恒星的袋子
I have in my hand a bag full of stars.
我要取出三颗砂粒
I'm going to take out three sand grains...
1 2 3…
one, two, three...
其它的丢掉
Throw the rest away...
这代表着离太阳最近的恒星
that represent our nearest stars.
半人马座比邻星离地球最近
Proxima Centauri is actually the closest star to Earth.
在目前比例下 它离我只是一步之遥
And on the scale of this analogy, it's about feet behind me,
所以我们把它扔到该在的位置
so we'll just toss Proxima Centauri to its proper place.
半人马座阿尔法星A
Alpha Centauri "A"
半人马座阿尔法星B
and Alpha Centauri "B"
按太阳就在4英里外的格里菲斯天文台这个比例
on this scale might be about two feet apart, while our Sun is
它们的间隔应该是大约2英尺
four miles away at Griffith observatory.
从这里看过去 代表着我们太阳的砂粒
From here, the sand grain representing our Sun
不可能看到
will be impossible to spot.
所以我们要利用上镜子
This is where the mirrors come in.
我们在阿尔法星A这里 去寻找我们的太阳
Here we are at Alpha Centauri, but now we have to find our own Sun.
瞧瞧他们能否把太阳指给我们看
Let's see if we can get them to show us the Sun.
喂 我是斯坦
Hello, it's Stan.
嘿 斯坦 我们看不到太阳
Hey, Stan, we can't see the Sun.
你是不是该把一些阳光照向我们？
You want to send us a little sunlight our way?
好的 太阳正照去你那里
Okay, Sun's coming your way.
还是看不到它
Can't see it yet.
啊 那里 看得很清楚
Uh, there. That was a good one, yeah.
很耀眼
Nice and bright.
噢 看那里
Wow, look at that.
真不可思议
That's incredible.
好的 斯坦 我们要给你看看阿尔法星A的光
Okay, Stan, we're going to show you the light of Alpha Centauri now.
是的 它在那
Yes, yes. There it is.
是 看到它了
Yep, we saw it.
- 他们看到它了 - 好极了
- They got it. - Awesome.
他看到阿尔法星A了
He sees Alpha Centauri.
在我们银河地区里
In our region of the Milky Way galaxy,
典型的恒星间距是3到5光年
the typical distance between stars ranges from three to five light-years.
对于砂粒般大小的恒星
With stars the size of sand grains,
我们在洛杉矶这样的城市里可以安放20颗
we could fit about 20 in a city like Los Angeles.
但如果有更多的恒星挤进来 稍微靠近地球的话
But if more stars crowded any closer to Earth,
对我们所知道的生命 这个辽阔的地区会变得危险起来
our cosmic neighborhood would become hazardous to life we know it.
超新星的开火 会烤热地球的大气层
Supernova going off, which would really cook the atmosphere.
如果有其它恒星以非常近的距离经过太阳
And if another star were to pass too close to the Sun,
那么行星的轨道会受到不利干扰
then the planetary orbits would be badly perturbed,
行星甚至会从太阳系走失 进入到星际空间里
planets could even be lost from the Sun, sent out into interstellar space.
这事千真万确 如果没有位于恒星之间的
It's really true that if we didn't have these vast amounts of real estate
这些数量庞大的不动产 我们可能不会在这里
between the stars, we likely wouldn't even be here.
用光行走一年来划分距离的远近
Cutting down the distance light travels in a year
能帮助我们对恒星有一个清晰的认识
helps put stars in a clearer context.
但同样的做法
But can we do the same
能让我们去应付实际上无限大的宇宙本身吗？
to grapple with the practically infinite dimensions of the universe itself?
银河的跨度是100 000光年
The Milky Way spans 100,000 light-years across.
而外面的另一个星系十分十分遥远
And the next galaxy over is really, really far away.
与银河类似且最靠近我们的星系
The distance to the nearest galaxy like our own... the nearest
是仙女座星系 它属于螺旋星系 距离我们约250万光年
spiral galaxy, the Andromeda galaxy... is about 2.5 million light-years away.
这几乎相当于银河系本身大小的25倍
That's about almost 25 times the size of the Milky Way itself.
所以 你要把25个银河系紧挨着排成一行
So if you lined up 25 Milky Ways end on end,
才能延伸到仙女座星系那里
that would stretch to the Andromeda galaxy.
或许比例要缩小得更多 情况才更清楚
It might be clearer to scale things down some more,
所以 把星系想象成美国各地的城市中心吧
and imagine galaxies as urban centers spread out across the United States.
有时 把星系当作是大城市
Sometimes galaxies are referred to as star cities,
这非常恰如其分
and that's a pretty good analogy.
如果假设银河象洛杉矶市那么大
If envision the Milky way galaxy at the size of the Los Angeles metropolitan area,
面积大约100平方英里
roughly 100 miles wide,
那么仙女座就会座落在纽约
then Andromeda would be in New York.
"本星系群"的其它成员
In between, would be other members of what astronomers call
将会位于两者之间
the "local group" of galaxies.
总的说来 本星系群中有两个主要角色
There's basically two major players in the local group.
分别是我们的银河系和仙女座星系
There's our galaxy... the Milky Way galaxy... and there's the Andromeda galaxy.
另外有一个较小的螺旋星系 它被称为三角座星系
There's another smaller spiral galaxy knows as M33.
此外 还有一些矮星系
And then we also have these dwarf galaxies,
它们或是含有1亿颗恒星 或是只有很少的几颗
which contain 100 million stars, sometimes even fewer.
但是 即使有如此广阔的距离
But even the vast distances
来分隔本星系群的成员
that separate members of the local group
也解救不了我们的银河家园
won't be enough to save our home galaxy.
仙女座星系和三角座星系都朝银河走来
Andromeda and M33 are both headed toward the Milky Way,
从现在算起 在几十亿年内
to the point where, in a few billion years from now,
它们会发生亲密接触
they're going to have a close encounter.
从宇宙规模来看 这次相遇似乎会很猛烈
On a cosmic scale, the collision seems violent.
但事实上 星系里的恒星分布如此稀疏
But in fact, the stars in the galaxies are so widely spaced,
它们会相互穿行而过 大部分会相安无事
they will weave past each other, largely undisturbed.
如果人类能存活这么长的时间
If humans survive that long,
他们在地球上几乎不会注意到这些
they'll hardly notice it here on Earth.
再过几十亿年之后 它们会合并为一个星系
And a few billion years after that, they'll have merged into a single galaxy.
我们现在的银河将不复存在
The Milky Way as we know it will cease to exist.
可是 到了那一刻
Until that time comes, though,
哪怕是本星系群里相距最近的星系 它们的间距
the distances between even the nearest galaxies of the local group
仍然超出我们的理解
remain beyond our grasp.
我们的星系邻居只是
And our galactic neighbors represent only a small sliver
广袤宇宙里的一小部分
of our immense cosmos.
在可观察到的那部分宇宙里
In the observable part of the universe,
有无数的物体 比如1 000亿个星系
there is something like 100 billion galaxies...
而每一个星系有数十亿的恒星
each with billions of stars.
如果宇宙能观察到的部分
If galaxies were spaced out
它里面的星系就是遍布美国的都市中心
like urban centers throughout the United States,
而它自己的面积也等同于美国
then to approximate the size of the observable universe,
那么宇宙这个国家的国土面积
the country would have to be large enough to wrap around the Earth
将足以包裹地球约500次
about 500 times.
把宇宙按比例缩小到人类习惯的规模
Shrinking the universe down to human scale
可能会帮助我们理解它的大小
may help us comprehend its size,
但即便如此 我们也做不到完全理解它
but reality, of course, doesn't work that way.
宇宙的广袤有时让我们觉得自己真小
The vastness of the universe sometimes makes us feel really small.
我们比太阳系小 比我们的银河小
We're small compared to the Solar System, small compared to
相比整个宇宙更是勿庸置疑
our galaxy, compared to the universe as a whole.
但从某些方面来说 我们也不要妄自菲薄
But in some ways, I think we're not insignificant,
因为我们是我们知道的唯一的生物
because we're the only creatures we know of
能拥有先进智慧 好奇心和理解力去研究宇宙
that have the advanced minds and curiosity and intellect to think about the universe.
在某种意义上
In a sense, we are the way
我们是宇宙为了解自身而创造的一个途径
in which the universe has found to know itself.
因此 对宇宙来说 终于可以开始去弄明白
And so that must mean the universe is finally
它自己有多么浩瀚 以至于让人惊叹不已
starting to figure out how awe-inspiringly vast it truly is.